thebluealliance.com 2018-11-26

# Privacy Policy - The Blue Alliance

Updated: **May 19, 2017**

### The short version

We collect your information only with your consent; we only collect the minimum amount of personal information that is necessary to fulfill the purpose of your interaction with us; we don't sell it to third parties; and we only use it as this Privacy Policy describes. Of course, the short version doesn't tell you everything, so please read on for more details! 

* * *

### What information The Blue Alliance collects and why

#### Information from website browsers

If you're **just browsing the website** , we collect the same basic information that most websites collect. We use common internet technologies, such as cookies and web server logs. This is stuff we collect from everybody, whether they have an account or not. 

The information we collect about all visitors to our website includes the visitor’s browser type, language preference, referring site, additional websites requested, and the date and time of each visitor request. We also collect potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. 

##### Why do we collect this?

We collect this information to better understand how our website visitors use The Blue Alliance, and to monitor and protect the security of the website. 

#### Information from users with accounts

We use Google sign-in for our accounts. If you **create an account** with us, only your email address is shared with us, not your password or any other personal information. You also have the option to give us more information, such as your name, which may include "User Personal Information." 

##### Why do we collect this?

  * We use your name to personalize your experience with The Blue Alliance.
  * We use your email address as a way to identify you across devices so that you can have a consistent experience across The Blue Alliance.
  * We use your email to communicate with you with information regarding approved suggestions and API key requests.

* * *

### What information The Blue Alliance does not collect

We do not intentionally collect sensitive personal information, such as social security numbers, genetic data, health information, or religious information. If you're a child under the age of 13, you may not have an account on The Blue Alliance. The Blue Alliance does not knowingly collect information from or direct any of our content specifically to children under 13. If we learn or have reason to suspect that you are a user who is under the age of 13, we will have to close your account. 

* * *

### How we share the information we collect

We **do not** share, sell, rent, or trade any User Personal Information with third parties. 

* * *

### Our use of cookies and tracking

#### Cookies

The Blue Alliance uses cookies to make interactions with our service easy and meaningful. We use cookies (and similar technologies, like HTML5 localStorage) to keep you logged in and remember your preferences. 

A cookie is a small piece of text that our web server stores on your computer or mobile device, which your browser sends to us when you return to our site. Cookies do not necessarily identify you if you are merely visiting The Blue Alliance; however, a cookie may store a unique identifier for each logged in user. The cookies The Blue Alliance sets are essential for the operation of the website, or are used for performance or functionality. By using our website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your computer or device. If you disable your browser or device’s ability to accept cookies, you will not be able to log in or use The Blue Alliance's services. 

#### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics as a third party tracking service, but we don’t use it to track you individually or collect your User Personal Information. We use Google Analytics to collect information about how our website performs and how our users, in general, navigate through and use The Blue Alliance. This helps us evaluate our users' use of The Blue Alliance; compile statistical reports on activity; and improve our content and website performance. 

Google Analytics gathers certain simple, non-personally identifying information over time, such as your IP address, browser type, internet service provider, referring and exit pages, time stamp, and similar data about your use of The Blue Alliance. We do not link this information to any of your personal information such as your user name. 

The Blue Alliance will not, nor will we allow any third party to, use the Google Analytics tool to track our users individually; collect any User Personal Information other than IP address; or correlate your IP address with your identity. Google provides further information about its own privacy practices and offers a browser add-on to opt out of Google Analytics tracking. 

Certain pages on our site may set other third party cookies. For example, we may embed content, such as videos, from another site that sets a cookie. While we try to minimize these third party cookies, we can’t always control what cookies this third party content sets. 

* * *

### License

This Privacy Policy is adapted from [GitHub's Privacy Statement](https://help.github.com/articles/github-privacy-statement/) and is licensed under the [Creative Commons Attribution license](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/). You may use it freely under the terms of the Creative Commons license. 

* * *

### Contact

Contact us if you have questions regarding our Privacy Policy.
